I'd have preferred a baby Cra,
but this is okay.
You've no idea how proud I am.
Your face makes it pretty clear.
I'm glad you made it in time, Dally.
Oh, that arm?
Yeah, you see, Rubi and I made a deal.
My freedom for his life, he got a bargain.
Don't pretend you're nasty.
We know you're a big softie Shushu.
There's no need to insult me, Eva.
So, what's next?
Now we've got Eva, Flopin and the baby,
we need to get out of here quickly.
Did you lose Ruel?
He was behind me. He should be along soon.
Dathura really seemed to have something
against him. I hope he's okay.
Arpagone, my friends need me.
And me? Don't you think I needed you
all these years? This isn't over.
No... not that. Not my pantie collection.
-Yugo?
-You could say that, yes.
I don't get it.
It's complicated,
but before I explain it all to you...
I must gather my brethren. It's time.
Ad...
Ad, it's time.
Yes, I heard you.
What are you going to do?
Are you sure, Oropo?
Once you fire the first shot,
there'll be no turning back.
My mind's been made up for centuries.
Mini-Dally!
Mini-Dally is a great name for little Iop!
Don't worry, kids.
We won't name him Mini-Dally.
You like the name, don't you?
Well, the thing is...
You said the first name you thought of.
Well, I like Mini-Dally. It's so cool!
The time is finally here!
My dear brothers and sisters,
it's time to reap what we've sown.
We've done the impossible,
but the hardest part still remains.
Once we've taken the gods' place,
we need to do better than they did.
We'll need to work together.
Come to me now.
You've won the right to witness a new era.
We still have things to settle here, Ruel.
The rest isn't important.
Arpagone, I beg you,
my friends need me right now.
I know, Ruel, you said so already.
Echo, bring Yugo to me.
Yugo!
-Echo took him.
-They're over there.
Kids, I'm counting on you
to watch your mother.
Goultard and I will end these guys,
then we'll go home.
Sipho, I need you to keep an eye
on Evangelyne and the children.
I know this must be confusing, Amalia,
but you can trust me on one thing.
What's that?
Yugo and I are truly one.
I feel what he feels.
I love Adamai as a brother,
Ruel as a father.
Dally and Evangelyne like my best friends.
But you, Amalia...
I have loved you forever.
I love you with a different kind of love.
The type of love that makes you
move worlds, overcome all difficulties.
You've enchanted me.
Oropo!
And now?
What exactly are you planning to do?
We're here, without knowing who you are
or where you're from.
Does it mean something?
What gives you the right
to talk to him like that?
Oropo doesn't have to answer you.
Calm down, Echo.
Everything'll be clear soon,
my dear Amalia.
Brethren, many years ago,
many, many years for some of you...
...I promised you a better world.
That time has come, my friends.
The Hyperzaap is complete.
In a few moments, you, the forgotten ones,
will replace the former gods.
Take the place of the gods?
You're completely out of your mind!
You still don't understand, Yugo.
It isn't you. It is we.
Don't you see that we are one?
One... Ad?
He's right. You're one.
I told you using the six Eliatrope Dofus
against Ogrest's Primordial Dofus
would have consequences.
Remember what happened
when you activated them?
Adamai, well--
Answer, Yugo, what happened?
I... I saw...
I saw Eliatropes...
Deep down you know what they are, right?
They're... versions of myself.
And there you have it.
As your brother explained, you weren't
ready to control the Dofus' power.
Your deepest desire, when you used them,
was to find your people.
For an instant,
the Dofus distorted your intentions.
Help me, Amalia.
Our birth was unique.
We came into the world already a few
years old, from an earlier existence.
Yours, Yugo.
Through a long corridor,
we were born at the dawn of time.
Disoriented by this voyage through time,
it was difficult for us to find our place.
For millennia,
we lived in fear of changing history.
And time passed and the more time went by,
the more we had access to your memories,
your desires, your loves,
we cherished them as much as you did,
except nothing belonged to us.
We grew and lived in your shadow, Yugo.
We baptized our species...
...the Eliotropes.
Leave her alone!
Stop!
Let me by, Ad. He needs to be stopped.
Listen, Yugo, you'd better think
about what you've learned just now.
I really don't want to fight you, Ad.
To fight Oropo,
you'll have to get past me.
Stay out of this.
Don't you see this hatred has blinded you?
Fight me, Yugo!
Yugo's over there!
Your lizard friend, I'll have to make him
pay for his treachery.
You must wait your turn.
Why do you get to go first?
He betrayed me first.
Maybe, but he kidnapped my kids
and hit Eva. That's worse.
Okay, you have a point.
Stop it!
I don't need you, Yugo.
One thing's for sure.
If Oropo and you really are one,
there's no reason for you to worry.
He's you, but more experienced and wiser.
I think we should hear what he has to say,
especially as Adamai is able to trust him.
Amalia...
And while he's telling his tale,
a weapon is forming behind him.
Oropo has an elite group of demigods,
and they really seem to believe in him.
What's our chance of stopping them?
Let's listen to our hearts,
not our fists, for once.
You're our father, Yugo.
Unfortunately,
we didn't get your longevity.
When Eliotropes die, their vital energy
is transferred to the others,
increasing their life expectancy.
I am the last Eliotrope.
All the others are gone.
What's that got to do with the gods?
Everything.
None of them listened to our prayers.
We died one after another
and no one cared.
Because the gods don't care
about their children.
They don't care about us,
even though we worship them.
Now it has to stop.
And you're the one to replace them,
is that it?
It will be you!
All of you. I'm afraid I won't be here
to see this momentous change.
You exude disapproval,
father of the Eliotropes.
Do you even feel any regret? After all,
you're responsible for all this.
Even your brother warned you.
That's enough!
Don't be so high and mighty, Oropo.
What's wrong with you, Echo?
You're lying through your teeth!
The power of the Eliacube,
combined with the six Eliatrope Dofus,
will create a blast that'll swallow
Inglorium and the gods too.
Shut up, Echo!
To take the gods' place,
you need to destroy them.
The only way to do that
is to cut off their followers.
What do you think will happen
when the Eliacube covers the Dofus?
You're building a bomb?
You could call it that.
That's not what I was told.
What did you think I meant
when I said replace them?
Give me back the Dofus!
Ad!
You traitor...
I forgive you.
What are you doing? You're insane!
I wasn't going to be surrounded
by demigods without protection.
Yugo!
Whew! Just in time for the party.
Looks like it.
All right, let's go, Goultard!
Goultard!
You're not the only one who's playing.
I'm not like you!
You need to take responsibility,
father of the Eliotropes.
You're no different to the gods
that rule us.
You created life
and left your children to their fate.
Who made you judge?
Who do you think you are?